<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rivm_item>
  <item>
    <item_title>RIVM launches study on coronavirus herd immunity</item_title>
    <item_link>http://www.rivm.nl/node/154191</item_link>
    <item_description>RIVMNational Institute for Public Health and the Environment
 has launched a large-scale study to investigate how many people have antibodies for the novel coronavirus. Invitations to take part in the study will be sent to 6,000 people from all over the country and from all age groups. In the coming months, RIVM will measure antibodies in the blood in several rounds of research.
    



</item_description>
    <item_pub_date>1585674900</item_pub_date>
    <item_guid>http://www.rivm.nl/node/154191</item_guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <item_title>Novel coronavirus found in wastewater</item_title>
    <item_link>http://www.rivm.nl/node/153991</item_link>
    <item_description>The novel coronavirus that causes COVID-19 has been detected in wastewater in the Netherlands, according to RIVMNational Institute for Public Health and the Environment
 research. A small percentage of patients with COVID-19 have the novel coronavirus in their gastrointestinal tract, and thus excrete it in their faeces.
  


</item_description>
    <item_pub_date>1585068589</item_pub_date>
    <item_guid>http://www.rivm.nl/node/153991</item_guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <item_title>A decrease in the number of tuberculosis patients in the Netherlands</item_title>
    <item_link>http://www.rivm.nl/node/153961</item_link>
    <item_description>In 2019, the number of people with tuberculosis (TB) in the Netherlands decreased to 759. This is 5 per cent less than in 2018, when 797 were reported. Of these patients, 445 had tuberculosis in the lungs, and 314 had extrapulmonary tuberculosis. These are the new annual key figures of RIVMNational Institute for Public Health and the Environment
.
  


</item_description>
    <item_pub_date>1585042065</item_pub_date>
    <item_guid>http://www.rivm.nl/node/153961</item_guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <item_title>Population screening programmes temporarily on hold</item_title>
    <item_link>http://www.rivm.nl/node/153721</item_link>
    <item_description>Due to the novel coronavirus (COVID-19) outbreak, the health care capacity in the Netherlands is expected to come under severe pressure in the coming period. That is why RIVMNational Institute for Public Health and the Environment
, by order of the Ministry of Health, Welfare and Sport, is temporarily discontinuing population screening for cervical, breast and colon&#xA0;cancer.
  


</item_description>
    <item_pub_date>1584446759</item_pub_date>
    <item_guid>http://www.rivm.nl/node/153721</item_guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <item_title>Additional measures novel coronavirus COVID-19</item_title>
    <item_link>http://www.rivm.nl/node/153501</item_link>
    <item_description>RIVMNational Institute for Public Health and the Environment
 has advised the Dutch government that additional measures are needed throughout the Netherlands to prevent the spread of COVID-19. The measures taken in Noord-Brabant now apply to the whole of the Netherlands.&#xA0;
    



</item_description>
    <item_pub_date>1584026042</item_pub_date>
    <item_guid>http://www.rivm.nl/node/153501</item_guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <item_title>Results of random sample test: 4% of hospital staff infected with coronavirus</item_title>
    <item_link>http://www.rivm.nl/node/153361</item_link>
    <item_description>Nearly four per cent of the hospital staff examined in Brabant is infected with the novel coronavirus (COVID-19). A random sample test by RIVMNational Institute for Public Health and the Environment
 &#xA0;between 6 and 9 March reveals this. The research findings support last Friday's implemented policy. It does, however, require a few additions.&#xA0;
    



</item_description>
    <item_pub_date>1583866919</item_pub_date>
    <item_guid>http://www.rivm.nl/node/153361</item_guid>
  </item>
</rivm_item>
